

# **Lindsey Benjamin**

### CI ENGINEER | QA ENGINEER | DEVELOPER



lindseylbenjamin@gmail.com



073 280 7522



lindsey-Ib.github.io/LBenjamin\_Porfolio/



linkedin.com/in/lindsey-benjamin-LB/

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am passionate and hard-working, with a strong belief that everything worth doing, is worth doing well. My strongest skills are problem-solving and critical thinking, and I am keen to expand these skills in a space which encourages innovation and collaboration. I have recently acquired some skills and experience in the field of coding and development, which I found to be a challenging and rewarding way to broaden my analytical thinking and problem-solving.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python OOP, ML, Django
- Java OOP, Agile, JDBC
- HTML/CSS Django
- SQL MySQL/PostgreSQL
- Version Control Git/Github
- Change Management
- Lean Manufacturing 5S, Visual Management, Autonomous Maintenance, Teamwork, Focussed Improvement, Quality Excellence, Team Training
- Problem-Solving DMAIC, Root-Cause Analysis, 5-Why
- ISO 9001 Internal Auditing
- Continuous Improvement PIPs
- Process Control SOP Development, Training & Assessment
- Product Quality QC Systems Development, Training & Assessment, CAPA

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Effective Communication
- Project Management
- Time Management
- Flexibility
- Analytical Thinking
- Leadership
- Critical Thinking
- High Performance Coaching

## Python Certified Associate Programmer (PCAP)

**PYTHON INSTITUTE** 

Python Certified Entry-Level Programmer (PCEP) **PYTHON INSTITUTE** 

**Software Engineering Bootcamp** 

**HYPERIONDEV** Jun 2020 - Jan 2021

**BTech: Mechanical Engineering** CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

**ND: Mechanical Engineering** 

Jul 2009 - Dec 2010

Aug 2022

Jun 2022

May 2011 - June 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer Intern

**BIZZSCHOLAR** May 2021 - March 2022

Developed backend of static page for website (go2f.net) using Django Framework.

Prepared and deployed static page on Heroku.

Developed parts of database for full website (go2f.net) using Django Framework and PostgreSQL.

Quality Assurance Engineer

**INDIGO BRANDS** Apr 2016 - Nov 2020

Led the business through its transition to Quality at Source systems.

Established and managed the Production QA team.

Performed internal and external auditing of Quality Management Systems.

Developed AQL agreements with suppliers of procured products and product packaging.

Developed quality standards and practices for new products and product lines.

**Continuous Improvement Engineer** 

**INDIGO BRANDS** Oct 2013 - Apr 2016

Led the pilot program to implement best practices such as 5S, Visual Management, Teamwork, Focused Improvement and Autonomous Maintenance.

Facilitated training workshops to train work teams in world class organisational best practices.

Identified short and long term improvement opportunities to improve manufacturing safety, quality, delivery lead times, and cost through the elimination of waste in the value stream.

Worked collaboratively with all departments to direct, improve, and control processes and performance.

Initiated and manage DMAIC projects for elimination of major wastes.

Developed standard operating procedures for production processes.

**Production Shift Manager** 

**INDIGO BRANDS** Jun 2013 - Sep 2013

Managed staff, production and quality targets to ensure targets are achieved.

Performed simple (such as 5-why) and complex (such as cause and effect diagrams and DMAIC) problem-solving where applicable.

**Process Controller** 

**INDIGO BRANDS** 

Formed part of a group of Mechanical Engineers responsible for the commissioning of the new high-

speed aerosol production line acquired by the business.

**EDUCATION** PERSONAL DETAILS

**Birth Date** 

17 January 1986

**Nationality** South African

**Address** 

46 De Wet Street. Bellville South

7530

CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Jan 2004 – Jun 2009